Guide to the William M. Citron Political Papers, 1918 - 1966
William M. Citron Political Papers, 1918 - 1966
- Biographical and Personal Materials, Series I.
  - Correspondence with biographical dictionaries (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Helen Citron (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - League of Women Voters--Correspondence, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - League of Women Voters--Newsletters, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - World War I--Correspondence and orders, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Diary, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - World War II--Correspondence and orders, 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - World War II--Articles, magazines, clippings, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Personal correspondence, Contributions, 1953-1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Harvard Activities--Correspondence and printed matter, 1954-1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Study of Austria--Articles, newspaper, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Jews and Anti-Semitism, Series II.
  - Friedrich Auhagen, 1935-1937 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Olympics, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Clippings and Printed Matter, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1939-1966 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, by year (Box 2, Folder 21-26)
  - Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Connecticut Valley Authority, Series III.
  - Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - FDR Letters re Connecticut River, 1935-1937 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Clippings, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Clippings, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1939-1961 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Clippings, 1939-1966 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Comprehensive Plan for Flood Control: Connecticut River Basin. New England Division--Corps of Engineers--War Department, Boston, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Congressional Business, Series IV.
  - Congressional Business, General, 1935-1938 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Works Progress Administration, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Textiles, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Middletown Postmastership, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Connecticut School Projects, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Catholic Persecution in Mexico, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Connecticut Tercentenary, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Middletown-Portland Bridge, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Duty On Lace, 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - New London Harbor, 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Europe, 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Office Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Public Works Administration, 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - West Point Applications, 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Civilian Conservation Corps, 1935-1937 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Thomas Dodd, 1935-1937 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Thames and Housatonic Rivers, 1935-1937 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Frigate Hartford, 1935-1938 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Polish, 1935-1938 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Old Saybrook, 1935-1938 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Bridgeport Slum Clearance, 1935-1938 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Merchant Marine Academy at New London, 1935-1938 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Labor, 1935-1939 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Letters of Congratulations, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - House Majority Leader, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Italians, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - James H. Bunce Correspondence, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Trade Agreements, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Individual Voting Record, 2 books (Box 6, Folder 66)
- Speeches and Press Releases, Series V.
  - Speeches and Press Releases, 1931-1932 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Speeches and Press Releases, 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Speeches and Press Releases, January-September 1936 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Speeches and Press Releases, October-December 1936 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Speeches and Press Releases, 1937-1951 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Speeches and Press Releases, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Speeches and Press Releases, 1953-1965 (Box 7, Folder 73)
- Politics and Campaigns, Series VI.
  - Politics, 1926-1930 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Campaign, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Political Correspondence, 1933-1934 (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Campaign--Publicity, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Testimonial Dinner, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Campaign--Correspondence, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Campaign--Publicity, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Political Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Campaign--Publicity, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Federal Judgeship, 1939-1940 (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Nomination, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Nomination, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Politics, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Politics, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Correspondence and Clippings re Politicians (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Campaign--Notes, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - Campaign--Endorsements, Funds, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Campaign--Publicity for Citron, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Campaign--General Publicity, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 92)
  - Campaign--Correspondence, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - Campaign--Correspondence, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 94)
  - Campaign--Engagements, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 95)
  - Campaign--Seely-Brown's Voting Record, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 96)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 97)
  - Politics, 1952-1963 (Box 11, Folder 98)
- Organizational and Civic Activities, Series VII.
  - American Jewish Committee, 1948-1965 (Box 12, Folder 99)
  - American Legion, 1945-1964 (Box 12, Folder 100)
  - B'nai B'rith, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 101)
  - Connecticut Bar Association, 1953-1966 (Box 12, Folder 102)
  - Council of Veterans Organizations, 1949-1963 (Box 12, Folder 103)
  - Disabled American Veterans, 1938-1970 (Box 12, Folder 104)
  - Infantile Paralysis Drive, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 105)
  - March of Dimes, PTA, 1946-1951 (Box 12, Folder 106)
  - Masons, 1920-1921 (Box 12, Folder 107)
  - Middlesex Bar Association, 1938-1956 (Box 12, Folder 108)
  - Middlesex County Law Library Association, 1958-1963 (Box 12, Folder 109)
  - Middlesex Grievance Committee, 1963-1966 (Box 12, Folder 110)
  - Middletown Bar Association, 1949-1952 (Box 12, Folder 111)
  - Middletown Sanitation District Commission, 1960-1964 (Box 12, Folder 112)
  - Military Order of the Purple Heart, 1950-1953 (Box 12, Folder 113)
  - Odd Fellows, 1935-1952 (Box 12, Folder 114)
  - Order of Ahepa, 1935-1938 (Box 12, Folder 115)
  - United Jewish Appeal, 1956-1960 (Box 12, Folder 116)
  - Zionist Organization of America, 1956-1957 (Box 12, Folder 117)
- Miscellaneous, Series VIII.
  - Correspondence, 1940-1963 (Box 13, Folder 118)
  - Clippings--Polish (Box 13, Folder 119)
  - Clippings--Labor, 1933-1938 (Box 13, Folder 120)
  - Clippings, 1931-1935 (Box 13, Folder 121)
  - Clippings, 1936-1940 (Box 13, Folder 122)
  - Clippings, 1941-1945 (Box 13, Folder 123)
  - Clippings, 1946-1950 (Box 13, Folder 124)
  - Clippings, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 125)
  - Clippings, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 126)
  - Clippings, 1956-1970 (Box 14, Folder 127)
  - Exhibit Folder (Box 14, Folder 128)
- Scrapbooks, Series IX.
  - Statements and other matters entered into the Congressional Record by Representative William H. Citron, Jan. 1935 - June 1936, 1938.; 13" x 21", 20 pages, one side; 20 blank pages remain.
    [Missing]
  - Clippings, chiefly from newspapers in Connecticut, 1934-1936.; 18" x 24 1/2", 30 leaves, most with clippings on both sides.
  - Clippings. Includes invitations to White House Receptions, 1935-1939.; 11" x 18", 150 pages, most with clippings on one side.